{"tossups": [{"question": "1. The earliest known text in this language, which invokes Nergal, appears next to foundation pegs known as the Urkish lions. For a while, the only known surviving long work in this language was an entry in the Amarna letters known as EA 24, which was written to Amenhotep III by its native speaker King Tushratta. This language was used to compose the Hymn to Nikkal, the oldest known substantial musical notation. The only other ancient language that appears to be genetically related to this one is (*) Urartian, with which it forms a family, though this non-Hittite language also appears on bilingual tablets found in Hattusa after its native speakers\u2019 subjugation by the Hittites. The primary worshippers of the god Kumarbi spoke, for 10 points, what language that shares its name with the main ethnic group of the Mitanni Empire?", "answer": "the Hurrian language &lt;AA, Ancient History&gt;", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "the <b><u>Hurrian language &lt;AA, Ancient History&gt;</u></b>", "acceptable": ["the Hurrian language &lt;AA, Ancient History&gt;", "Hurrian language &lt;AA, Ancient History&gt;"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "2. This work implies that a group who \u201ccopulated ecstatic and insatiate with a bottle of beer a package of cigarettes a candle\u201d were largely homosexual, in noting that they \u201clost their loveboys to the three old shrews of fate,\u201d with one of those \u201cshrews\u201d being the \u201cheterosexual dollar.\u201d This work likens \u201cvisions,\u201d \u201cdreams,\u201d and \u201cnew loves\u201d to wreckage that breaks on \u201cthe rocks of Time\u201d after they have \u201cgone down the American river,\u201d and compares Jesus\u2019 laments to jazz in describing an (*) \u201celi eli lama sabachthani saxophone cry.\u201d This poem\u2019s second section opens mentioning a \u201csphinx of cement and aluminum\u201d while its first opens mentioning friends who were \u201cstarving hysterical naked.\u201d The speaker repeats \u201cI\u2019m with you in Rockland\u201d in, for 10 points, what Beat poem that says \u201cI saw the best minds of my generation destroyed by madness?\u201d", "answer": "\u201cHowl\u201d &lt;WA, Poetry&gt;", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>\u201cHowl\u201d &lt;WA, Poetry&gt;</u></b>", "acceptable": ["\u201cHowl\u201d &lt;WA, Poetry&gt;", "\u201cHowl\u201d &lt;WA, Poetry&gt;"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "3. This man\u2019s description of an encounter with Betty Mitchell is one of many erotic passages he wrote partly in French and Spanish, which reflect his extensive interest in Spain, much like his extensive collection of chapbooks and Spanish plays. This man\u2019s writings have generally superseded similar works by John Evelyn that cover the same era, and describe an annual celebration of the removal of a kidney stone. His work, which he discontinued for fear of becoming (*) blind, was deciphered by Reverend John Smith from a system of tachygraphy created by Thomas Shelton and details his service as Chief Secretary of the Admiralty during the Anglo-Dutch War. For 10 points, identify this important primary source on the Plague and Great Fire of London, an English diarist.", "answer": "Samuel Pepys [peeps] &lt;WA, Historical Sources&gt;", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Samuel Pepys &lt;WA, Historical Sources&gt;</u></b> [peeps]", "acceptable": ["Samuel Pepys &lt;WA, Historical Sources&gt;", "Samuel Pepys &lt;WA, Historical Sources&gt;"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "4. Along with Wilhelm Meister, The New Heloise, and Don Quixote, this novel was purportedly Arthur Schopenhauer\u2019s favorite, so much so that he asked his publisher to translate it to German. An entire paragraph in this book is filled with asterisks meant to represent the thoughts of one character. The phrase \u201cevery ball has its billet\u201d is from this novel and is also quoted on the first page of Diderot\u2019s (*) Jacques the Fatalist, which borrowed an entire passage from this novel. An episode in this novel focuses on Hafen Slawkenbergius, who wrote an entire treatise on noses. The 11 volumes that make up this novel were written over a period of 8 years. The title character of this novel is born with an abnormally flat nose, thanks to Dr. Slop, who made a mistake with his forceps while delivering him. For 10 points, name this novel about the \u201clife and opinions\u201d of the title character, written by Laurence Sterne.", "answer": "The Life and Opinions of Tristram Shandy, Gentleman &lt;SB, LongFic&gt;", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Life and Opinions of Tristram Shandy, Gentleman &lt;SB, LongFic&gt;</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Life and Opinions of Tristram Shandy, Gentleman &lt;SB, LongFic&gt;", "Life and Opinions of Tristram Shandy, Gentleman &lt;SB, LongFic&gt;"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "5. This group is synonymous with a group designated quirites in older sources. People who claimed to belong to this group, but whose pleas were ignored and made to work in stone quarries, are defended from the title man by the speeches of In Verrem. By definition, peregrini were not part of this group. People in this group could be designated as either optimo iure [OP-tee-moh YOO-ray] or non optimo iure. A phrase affirming that someone belonged to this group names an (*) address that justified a blockade of Piraeus and asserted the \u201cstrong arm\u201d of a certain country. Some members of this group were designated \u201csine suffragio.\u201d The Antonine Constitution, which made all members of the Roman Empire into members of this group, was created by the emperor Caracalla. For 10 points, give this privileged status afforded to free individuals in the Roman Republic.", "answer": "Roman citizens [or civis romanus or cives romani or civitas romana; accept Civis romanus sum or Civitas sine suffragio] &lt;WA, Ancient History&gt;", "subcategory": "History Classical", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Roman citizens &lt;WA, Ancient History&gt;</u></b> [or <b><u>civis romanus</u></b> or <b><u>cives romani</u></b> or <b><u>civitas romana</u></b>; accept <b><u>Civis romanus sum</u></b> or <b><u>Civitas sine suffragio</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Roman citizens &lt;WA, Ancient History&gt;", "Roman citizens &lt;WA, Ancient History&gt;", "civis romanus", "cives romani", "civitas romana", "Civis romanus sum", "Civitas sine suffragio"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "6. The notes to this play state that it has rendered in English a \u201cplay in sundrie languages,\u201d as a character earlier specifies that \u201ceach of us must act his part in unknown languages.\u201d Douglas Bruster cited copying of sloppy handwriting in re-attributing anonymous \u201cadditional passages\u201d that were added to this play\u2019s fourth edition that were once credited to Ben Jonson. The monologue opening this play describes a katabasis where \u201cPluto was pleased\u201d and sealed the speaker\u2019s passport \u201cwith a kisse.\u201d A lover is revealed by a bribe to the servant (*) Pendringano in this play, in which a man bites out his own tongue after the King summons torturers. This play preempted elements of Hamlet by including characters such as the ghost of Andrea and the spirit Revenge, and containing a performance of the play Soliman and Perseda. \u201cHieronimo is mad againe\u201d is the alternate title of, for 10 points, what horrifically violent Thomas Kyd play?", "answer": "The Spanish Tragedy, or, Hieronimo is mad againe &lt;WA, Drama&gt;", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Spanish Tragedy, or, Hieronimo is mad againe &lt;WA, Drama&gt;</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Spanish Tragedy, or, Hieronimo is mad againe &lt;WA, Drama&gt;", "Spanish Tragedy, or, Hieronimo is mad againe &lt;WA, Drama&gt;"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "7. In this modern city\u2019s outskirts, a gravesite holds the bones of the apocryphal Sage Kija, considered the first settler of this city\u2019s region. According to the Memorabilia of the Three Kingdoms, the site of this city contained the first capital of the legendary Tangun Dynasty. 200,000 residents of this city were forcibly resettled in 668 CE, after which it became the capital of the Protectorate to Pacify the East. A winged horse statue in this city carrying two workers on its back symbolizes the desired \u201cspeed\u201d of the (*) Cheollima [chuh-lee-mah] System. This city was the site of the second major land battle of the Sino-Japanese War, which followed Qing forces crossing the Yalu River. International Worker\u2019s Day lends its name to this city\u2019s Rungrado First of May Stadium, the largest such venue in the world. For 10 points, name this city in which the Juche Tower overlooks the Taedong River, the capital of North Korea.", "answer": "Pyongyang &lt;AA, World History&gt;", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Pyongyang &lt;AA, World History&gt;</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Pyongyang &lt;AA, World History&gt;", "Pyongyang &lt;AA, World History&gt;"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "8. A 143-line poem in this language is structured as a metered list of kings, including \u201cCaesar ruled the Greeks,\u201d after mentioning its title scop, or poet. A five-line poem called one man\u2019s \u201cDeath Song\u201d is the best-attested poem in this language, ahead of a nine-line one that opens by honoring the \u201cguardian of heaven.\u201d A poem in this language describes a gift of eight horses with golden bridles, including one with a jeweled saddle, and opens by detailing the submission of people beyond the \u201cwhale-road.\u201d Another poem in this language describes heroics at the (*) Battle of Maldon. This language was used by an illiterate cowherd to compose Caedmon\u2019s Hymn. A funeral at the seashore opens a poem in this language whose central hero partners with Wiglaf to slay a dragon and defends the mead-hall Heorot [HAIR-oht]. For 10 points, name this language used to write Beowulf.", "answer": "Old English [do not accept or prompt on \u201cMiddle English\u201d or \u201cEnglish\u201d] (the first line refers to the Widsith) &lt;WA, HistInLit&gt;", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Old English &lt;WA, HistInLit&gt;</u></b> [do not accept or prompt on \"Middle English\" or \"English\"]", "acceptable": ["Old English &lt;WA, HistInLit&gt;", "Old English &lt;WA, HistInLit&gt;"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": ["Middle English", "English"], "metadata": "the first line refers to the Widsith"}, {"question": "9. A traditionalist faction in this present-day U.S. state led by Chitto Harjo, also known as \u201cCrazy Snake,\u201d was opposed by Pleasant Porter. David Gran\u2019s 2017 book Killers of the Flower Moon details how a string of over 50 murders in this state during the 1920s organized by William Hale contributed to the \u201cbirth of the FBI.\u201d This state was unified thanks to an \u201cEnabling Act\u201d which put its capital in the railroad town of Guthrie. Earlier, parts of this state tried to join the U.S. as the state of (*) Sequoyah, in advance of the Curtis Act scheduling the 1906 dismantling of tribal governments. People coveting the oil wealth of Native Americans in this state committed a string of murders in its Osage County. Its namesake territory was settled en masse during an 1889 land rush. For 10 points, what state contains the Indian Territory that was the destination of the Cherokees who walked the Trail of Tears?", "answer": "Oklahoma [accept Oklahoma Territory; prompt on OK] &lt;WA, US History&gt;", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Oklahoma &lt;WA, US History&gt;</u></b> [accept <b><u>Oklahoma Territory</u></b>; prompt on <u>OK</u>]", "acceptable": ["Oklahoma &lt;WA, US History&gt;", "Oklahoma &lt;WA, US History&gt;", "Oklahoma Territory"], "promptable": ["OK"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "10. From 1918 to 1921, 1.5 million people of this ethnicity left the Catholic Church, with most joining a state church sponsored by a leader whose motto was \u201cdo not fear and do not steal.\u201d Secret worship by religious dissidents of this ethnicity was aided by the Unity of Brethren, who were notably not allowed to practice publicly, unlike Lutherans, by the Patent of Toleration. A group of soldiers mainly of this ethnicity helped spread secular ideas after returning from service in the Imperial Russian and (*) White Russian armies; that group of soldiers is known as a \u201cLegion.\u201d Nobility of this ethnicity became mostly Catholic again in the 17th century when 600 Calvinist noble families emigrated after Frederick the \u201cWinter King\u201d lost at the Battle of White Mountain. For 10 points, name this ethnic group that produced such religious leaders as Jan Hus.", "answer": "Czechs [prompt on Bohemians or Moravians] &lt;WA, Continental History&gt;", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Czechs &lt;WA, Continental History&gt;</u></b> [prompt on <u>Bohemians</u> or <u>Moravians</u>]", "acceptable": ["Czechs &lt;WA, Continental History&gt;", "Czechs &lt;WA, Continental History&gt;"], "promptable": ["Bohemians", "Moravians"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "11. This character goes on many dates with a woman who makes him promise to think about her when he masturbates next time, and whom he earlier lent his notebook in History of Drama class. Most of a novel\u2019s fifth chapter consists of a letter to this character from his girlfriend detailing daily activities like vegetable farming and sports. This character often goes to bars to chase girls with a serially unfaithful friend who studies for the Foreign Ministry, with whom he bonded over a mutual love of (*) F. Scott Fitzgerald. At the beginning of the novel, this man rooms with a geography major who stutters every time he tries to say the word \u201cmap,\u201d a character called \u201cStorm Trooper.\u201d Near the novel\u2019s end, this character hooks up with the music teacher Reiko, who left a sanatorium after Naoko committed suicide. For 10 points, name this protagonist of Haruki Murakami\u2019s Norwegian Wood.", "answer": "Toru Watanabe [accept either underlined portion] &lt;WA, LongFic&gt;", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Toru Watanabe &lt;WA, LongFic&gt;</u></b> [accept <b><u>either underlined portion</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Toru Watanabe &lt;WA, LongFic&gt;", "Toru Watanabe &lt;WA, LongFic&gt;", "either underlined portion"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "12. This essay quotes the lines \u201ca drab of state, a cloth-o-silver slut\u201d from Thomas Middleton\u2019s play, The Revenger\u2019s Tragedy, after criticizing another author\u2019s avoidance of any form of inconvenience. This essay compares one civic duty to \u201ccheckers or backgammon, with a slight moral tinge to it.\u201d This essay criticizes the arguments for expediency in a tract by William Paley. This essay, originally delivered as a lecture to the Concord Lyceum, states that \u201cit matters not how small the beginning may seem to be\u201d after claiming that a (*) single man\u2019s decision to cease holding slaves would certainly lead to the abolition of slavery. It begins by affirming the motto \u201cthat government is best which governs least\u201d and informs the reader about how the author spent a night in jail after not paying taxes for 6 years. For 10 points, name this essay about resisting government, written by Henry David Thoreau.", "answer": "\u201cCivil Disobedience\u201d &lt;SB, Essays/Crit&gt;", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>\u201cCivil Disobedience\u201d &lt;SB, Essays/Crit&gt;</u></b>", "acceptable": ["\u201cCivil Disobedience\u201d &lt;SB, Essays/Crit&gt;", "\u201cCivil Disobedience\u201d &lt;SB, Essays/Crit&gt;"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "13. The only known source of this material in all of Mesoamerica is along the Motagua River, which produces a \u201cblue\u201d variety of it. A river named for the \u201cwhite\u201d form of this material historically supplied the town of Khotan. Pacal the Great\u2019s mask is made of this material. An object owned by King Zhao Mo of Nanyue [non-y\u2019way] made of this material was laced together with gold (*) wires, representing a trend started in the Eastern Zhou and continued in the Han dynasty. Chinese nobility were often buried in suits made of this material, whose appearance is imitated by celadon pottery. This material also names a member of the Three Pure Ones. For 10 points, name this stone associated with an emperor in Daoist cosmology, a stone that is valuable and green.", "answer": "jade [or jadeite; accept blue jade or white jade] &lt;WA, Archaeology&gt;", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>jade &lt;WA, Archaeology&gt;</u></b> [or <b><u>jadeite</u></b>; accept <b><u>blue jade</u></b> or <b><u>white jade</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["jade &lt;WA, Archaeology&gt;", "jade &lt;WA, Archaeology&gt;", "jadeite", "blue jade", "white jade"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "14. At the end of his essay \u201cSun and Steel,\u201d Yukio Mishima inserted a poem titled for this figure that begins by asking, \u201cDo I then, belong to the heavens?\u201d Edward Field wrote a poem that imagines this figure living in the 21st century who \u201cnow rides commuter trains / serves on various committees, / And wishes he had drowned.\u201d Brian Greene\u2019s children\u2019s book about a young boy who escapes his space-home to explore a black hole was adapted into a 2010 movie by the film duo AL and AL and is named for [This Figure] at the Edge of (*) Time. The speaker of one poem imagines a man who does not think of this figure\u2019s fall as \u201can important failure\u201d and notes that \u201cdogs go on with their doggy life.\u201d William Carlos William wrote a poem titled on a painting about this figure created by Pieter Brueghel. For 10 points name this mythological figure who flew too close to the sun, the son of Daedalus.", "answer": "Icarus &lt;SB, Literary Legacy&gt;", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Icarus &lt;SB, Literary <b><u>Legacy&gt;</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Icarus &lt;SB, Literary Legacy&gt;", "Legacy&gt;"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "15. Description acceptable. A distinct \u201cPhiladelphia Approach\u201d to implementing this sort of initiative was exemplified by the 1959 East Poplar scheme. A 1958 article in Life profiled Dick Lee as the \u201cchampion\u201d of implementing this sort of initiative in New Haven, which used more federal money than any other similar program. The opening to a book opposing these initiatives describes how an \u201celaborately learned superstition\u201d has deceived policymakers in the context of discussing the author\u2019s experience in the North End of (*) Boston. Federal financing of these initiatives was [emphasize] first established under the Fair Deal by Title I of the Housing Act of 1949 and expanded by several highway bills. A book written to oppose these initiatives described a phenomenon called the \u201cballet of the sidewalks\u201d in Greenwich Village. For 10 points, Jane Jacobs\u2019 opposition to what type of initiative prompted her to write The Death and Life of Great American Cities?", "answer": "urban renewal programs [or urban regeneration or urban revitalization or slum clearing; accept city clean-up; accept any answer that refers to tearing down slums and/or large parts of cities; prompt on urban planning; prompt on answers that mention housing or public housing or affordable housing] &lt;WA, US History&gt;", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>urban renewal programs &lt;WA, US History&gt;</u></b> [or <b><u>urban regeneration</u></b> or <b><u>urban revitalization</u></b> or <b><u>slum clearing</u></b>; accept <b><u>city clean-up</u></b>; accept <b><u>any answer that refers to tearing down slums and/or large parts of cities</u></b>; prompt on <u>urban planning</u>; prompt on <u>answers that mention housing</u> or <u>public housing</u> or <u>affordable housing</u>]", "acceptable": ["urban renewal programs &lt;WA, US History&gt;", "urban renewal programs &lt;WA, US History&gt;", "urban regeneration", "urban revitalization", "slum clearing", "city clean-up", "any answer that refers to tearing down slums and/or large parts of cities"], "promptable": ["urban planning", "answers that mention housing", "public housing", "affordable housing"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "16. In a play titled for this word, a character recounts a time when his mother found the name of his Jewish childhood crush in his notebook and spat in his face, and a painter has her husband pose for a portrait modeled after Velazquez\u2019s portrait of Juan de Pareja. In a novel titled for this feeling, the protagonist watches a soccer match between the Bushbucks and Sundown with a \u201cdog-man.\u201d The main character of a play titled for this feeling beats his cheating wife Emily, who paints portraits at a mosque led by Imam (*) Fareed. In a novel titled for this feeling, a professor is relieved to see his name misspelled in the newspaper after three men burn down his daughter\u2019s farmhouse. This feeling titles an Ayad Akhtar play and a novel in which Melanie Isaacs has an affair with a Lord Byron scholar. For 10 points, give this word which titles a novel about Professor David Lurie, written by J.\u00a0M.\u00a0Coetzee.", "answer": "disgrace [accept Disgrace or Disgraced] &lt;SB, Miscellaneous Lit&gt;", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>disgrace &lt;SB, Miscellaneous Lit&gt;</u></b> [accept <b><u>Disgrace</u></b> or <b><u>Disgraced</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["disgrace &lt;SB, Miscellaneous Lit&gt;", "disgrace &lt;SB, Miscellaneous Lit&gt;", "Disgrace", "Disgraced"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "17. Lionel Trilling read \u201cadmiration and envy\u201d into a homoerotic passage by an author with this first name describing \u201clong legs like girls sheathed to the neck\u201d and \u201cbeauty of his giant\u2019s body.\u201d In that story by an author with this first name, a former law student commands a peasant woman to roast an animal whose neck he breaks with his boot. A story by an author with this first name notes that Eve gave birth just after her wedding with Adam, much like how a town prostitute gives birth seventeen weeks after marriage. An author with this first name described a man\u2019s initiation into a (*) Cossack troop in \u201cMy First Goose.\u201d This is the first name of the author of the author of Red Cavalry, as well as an author who wrote about how the \u201cSpirit of Evil\u201d convinces the title character to put urine in the town\u2019s bread. For 10 points, give this first name of the Yiddish-language author of \u201cGimpel the Fool.\u201d", "answer": "Isaac [or Yitzhak; accept Isaac Babel or Isaac Bashevis Singer] &lt;WA, Short Fiction&gt;", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Isaac &lt;WA, Short Fiction&gt;</u></b> [or <b><u>Yitzhak</u></b>; accept <b><u>Isaac Babel</u></b> or <b><u>Isaac Bashevis Singer</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Isaac &lt;WA, Short Fiction&gt;", "Isaac &lt;WA, Short Fiction&gt;", "Yitzhak", "Isaac Babel", "Isaac Bashevis Singer"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "18. In this conflict, a phrase translated as \u201cwiping the slate clean\u201d was used to refer to the mass killing of Bambuti. A party in this conflict executed a daring operation to land commandos in civilian-esque aircraft and capture an airfield in Kitona. A military advisor to one of this war\u2019s leaders was fired in favor of the leader\u2019s brother-in-law, Celestin Kifwa; that spurned advisor, James Kabarebe, fought on this conflict\u2019s other side. The leader of one side in this war was assassinated by his (*) kadogo child soldier bodyguards, leaving his son to negotiate a peace process concluded by the Sun City Agreement, the Pretoria Accord, and the Luanda Agreement. This war was preceded by one in which Rwanda and Uganda responded to the militancy of genocidaire-filled refugee camps by invading Zaire and overthrowing Mobutu Sese Seko. For 10 points, name this deadliest post-World War II conflict involving nine African countries, which occurred primarily in its namesake country from 1998 to 2003.", "answer": "Second Congo War [or Great War of Africa; or Great African War; or African World War; prompt on Congo War] &lt;AA, World History&gt;", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Second Congo War &lt;AA, World History&gt;</u></b> [or <b><u>Great War of Africa</u></b>; or <b><u>Great African War</u></b>; or <b><u>African World War</u></b>; prompt on <u>Congo War</u>]", "acceptable": ["Second Congo War &lt;AA, World History&gt;", "Second Congo War &lt;AA, World History&gt;", "Great War of Africa", "Great African War", "African World War"], "promptable": ["Congo War"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "19. The Martinican philosopher Edouard Glissant wrote a book about visiting this author\u2019s home of Rowan Oak. In a speech, this author stated that our tragedy today is \u201ca universal physical fear so long sustained by now that we can even bear it.\u201d The Blotner papers, named for the man who wrote a comprehensive biography of this author, can be found at the Center for [this author\u2019s] Studies at Southeast Missouri State University. Cleanth Brooks wrote three books on this author, two of which are partly titled for a (*) fictional location created by him, whose name is derived from two Chickasaw words meaning \u201csplit land.\u201d That county is also where outcasts created by this author, like Joanna Burden and Joe Christmas, as well as the Compson and Bundren families lived. For 10 points, name this creator of Yoknapatawpha [YAWK-nuh-pah-TAW-fuh] County, the author of As I Lay Dying.", "answer": "William Faulkner &lt;SB, Authors/Bios&gt;", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "William Faulkner &lt;SB, <b><u>Authors/Bios&gt;</u></b>", "acceptable": ["William Faulkner &lt;SB, Authors/Bios&gt;", "Authors/Bios&gt;"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "20. A proposed \u201csociology\u201d of this concept had its funding blocked by Senators including Jesse Helms, prompting Edward Laumann to seek funding from the MacArthur Foundation before publishing in 1994. A \u201cparticularly neurotic\u201d relationship between work and this concept is demonstrated in Anne McClintock\u2019s Imperial Leather, whose subtitle refers to race, gender, and this. A book titled for this concept illustrates attitudes toward it with the methods of Tommaso Tamburini and the \u201cphilanthropic\u201d movement in Germany, before a shift in (*) discourse in the 19th century that used terms such as \u201cnervous disorders.\u201d That book titled for this concept, whose introduction refers to \u201cWe Other Victorians,\u201d traces attitudes toward of it via the framework of a \u201crepressive hypothesis.\u201d The titles of both Kinsey Reports refer to, for 10 points, what topic, the subject of a \u201cHistory\u201d by Michel Foucault that investigates the \u201cuses of pleasure?\u201d", "answer": "(human) sexuality [or sex or sexual behavior; do not accept or prompt on \u201chomosexuality\u201d or \u201clesbianism,\u201d as all these books explore sexual behavior in general] &lt;WA, Phil/SS&gt;", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>sexuality &lt;WA, Phil/SS&gt;</u></b> [or <b><u>sex</u></b> or <b><u>sexual behavior</u></b>; do not accept or prompt on \"homosexuality\" or \"lesbianism,\u201d as all these books explore sexual behavior in general\"]", "acceptable": ["sexuality &lt;WA, Phil/SS&gt;", "sexuality &lt;WA, Phil/SS&gt;", "sex", "sexual behavior"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": ["homosexuality", "lesbianism,\u201d as all these books explore sexual behavior in general"], "metadata": "human"}, {"question": "21. Fernand Braudel\u2019s characterization of this modern-day country as a \u201ccity-state writ large\u201d was argued to be misleading by Jonathan Israel in a book on its \u201cprimacy.\u201d Shipping in this modern-day country was greatly improved by the development of a ship whose name meant \u201cflute.\u201d Imports of raw goods, such as timber, that passed through this country are characterized by historians as its \u201cmother trade.\u201d Conventionally, this country is considered to have produced the world\u2019s first (*) limited liability company, which was founded in 1602 and publicly traded on its stock exchange. This country maintained dominion over Ceylon from 1640 to 1796 thanks to conquests by the VOC, its East India Company. Poulders enabled the agriculture of, for 10 points, what country whose 17th century \u201cGolden Age\u201d featured such painters as Rembrandt?", "answer": "The Netherlands [or Kingdom of the Netherlands; or The United Provinces or Verenigde Provinci\u00ebn] &lt;WA, Continental History&gt;", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "The Netherlands &lt;WA, Continental <b><u>History&gt;</u></b> [or <b><u>Kingdom of the Netherlands</u></b>; or <b><u>The United Provinces</u></b> or <b><u>Verenigde Provinci\u00ebn</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["The Netherlands &lt;WA, Continental History&gt;", "History&gt;", "Kingdom of the Netherlands", "The United Provinces", "Verenigde Provinci\u00ebn"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "22. At the end of a novel from this country, nihilistic youths decide that nothing is worth running for, then immediately run after a missed cable car; that book from here deals with accidental incest in the aristocratic Maia family. In a novel from this country, a doctor quits his job to wander the streets of its capital after learning of the death of an author, but then befriends that author\u2019s ghost, who explains how he created his various writing personas or (*) \u201cheteronyms.\u201d This is the home country of the eccentric author of The Book of Disquiet, as well as a novelist who described people voting with a series of blank ballots after a plague which affects the girl with the dark glasses, but not the doctor\u2019s wife. For 10 points, name this country whose writers include Jos\u00e9 Maria de E\u00e7a de Queiroz, Fernando Pessoa, and the author of Blindness, Jos\u00e9 Saramago.", "answer": "(Republic of) Portugal &lt;JC, LongFic&gt;", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Portugal &lt;JC, <b><u>LongFic&gt;</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Portugal &lt;JC, LongFic&gt;", "LongFic&gt;"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "Republic of"}, {"question": "23. The father of a ruler of this region died while trying to escape a tower with a rope of knotted sheets. To mock a prophecy, the severed head of a ruler of this region was supposedly crowned with ivy and placed in a pillory. A leader from this region was promised the western lands demarcated by Tripartite Indenture, which he negotiated with the father of the knight \u201cHotspur.\u201d Accounts disagree about what happened to the missing head of a leader from this region who died at Orewin Bridge. (*) Common law was introduced into this region following its conquest via the Statute of Rhuddlan [RITH-lahn]. The eastern borderlands of this region were governed by Marcher Lords, and include an earthwork called Offa\u2019s Dyke built to protect Mercia from this region\u2019s bandits. Owain Glynd\u0175r [OH-ain glind-OOR] was the last native claimant to be \u201cPrince\u201d of, for 10 points, what region ruled by Llywelyn the Last?", "answer": "Wales [or Cymru] &lt;JC, British/Other History&gt;", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "Wales &lt;JC, British/Other <b><u>History&gt;</u></b> [or <b><u>Cymru</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Wales &lt;JC, British/Other History&gt;", "History&gt;", "Cymru"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "24. This poet presented an extreme version of sola fide doctrine in the form of a speaker who states \u201cI have God\u2019s warrant, could I blend / all hideous sins, as in a cup / To drink the mingled venoms up.\u201d Another of this poet\u2019s speakers muses \u201cOr, there\u2019s Satan! --one might venture / pledge one\u2019s soul to him\u201d before being interrupted by vespers. The speaker talks of bargaining \u201cfor his love, and stand / Paying a price, at his right hand?\u201d in a poem this author framed as a meditation by Martin Luther\u2019s friend (*) Johannes Agricola. He used the exclamation \u201cG-r-r!\u201d to open the first and last lines of a poem about hatred of Brother Lawrence. His jealous speakers include a monk in \u201cSoliloquy of the Spanish Cloister\u201d and a nobleman who notes the title figure is \u201cpainted on the wall / Looking as if she were alive. I call.\u201d For 10 points, name this poet whose collection Men and Women contains \u201cMy Last Duchess.\u201d", "answer": "Robert Browning &lt;WA, Poetry&gt;", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Robert Browning &lt;WA, <b><u>Poetry&gt;</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Robert Browning &lt;WA, Poetry&gt;", "Poetry&gt;"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}